WWW.MY-SUBS.CO
Well, she's gone now.
Oh, that's a shame.
Nothing for me, Mr Carson?
No, Anna.
Once again, I'm afraid,
there's nothing for you.
Come on.
I've enough on my plate
without going into details.
You're co-owner of this estate.
You have to get into detail.
Not to challenge Robert, surely? No,
but you have to pull your weight.
That's all I'm saying.
How is Bates? I've not seen him
for a while, sir.
Oh? Why's that?
I'm not quite sure, sir.
They've stopped his visitors.
Has he given you a reason?
He's not written
in quite some time now.
And you don't know why? No, but
I'm certain I will before too long.
Mrs Crawley, how may I help?
I'm sorry to push in on you again.
I didn't have time
to come down before dinner
and now we're on our way home.
Oh.
Mrs Hughes, you know
I went to see Ethel Parks?
I do, ma'am. She wouldn't
speak to me then
but she has since sought me out
and asked me to deliver
this letter to you.
When we last spoke of her,
you seemed to think
she'd fallen into bad ways.
I'm afraid that's the case.
She's been working as a prostitute.
My, my. That's not a word you hear
in this house every day. No.
But I think it also shows
the measure of her misery.
Ethel has been driven into this,
of that I have no doubt.
If only she would allow me
to help her, but she won't.
If this letter can give a clue as to
how I may help, please let me know.
I will, ma'am.
Your sentiments do you credit,
but I suspect
she will be too ashamed
to face how far she's fallen.
Good night.
Good night, Mrs Crawley.
So, am I to answer to you both?
Of course not.
What Lord Grantham means
is that I've made an investment
in the estate. That is all.
Otherwise, nothing has changed.
Very good.
Can we bring the staff
back up to snuff?
and I need a new footman.
Do you really?
I sometimes feel the world
is different than it was
before the War.
I would like to return
to my duties as a butler, sir,
but if you prefer I continue to do
the work of a second footman
in addition... Mr Crawley does not
mean that, do you?
Certainly not. That is good news.
It's too late to get into shape
before the dinner
for the Archbishop of York,
but it'll be the last time
you'll have to fudge it.
I'll do my best with an added
spring in my step.
Why don't you have breakfast in bed?
Because I'm not married.
Yes, but now that... The others are,
what difference would it make?
You know what I mean.
I prefer to be up and about.
Tennessee is going to
ratify the 19th Amendment. Meaning?
All US women will have the vote.
Which is more than here.
They almost do.
I don't have the vote. I'm not over
30 and I'm not a householder.
It's ridiculous. You should write
to the Times.
Maybe I will.
Ask your mother if she needs
any help with tonight's dinner.
There's nothing so toffee-nosed
as a prince of the Church.
Put him next to your grandmother.
She'll handle him.
Oh, Anna. You'll be happy to hear as
soon as we take on a new house maid
you'll be a lady's maid
to Lady Mary at last.
That's nice, Mr Carson. Thank you.
I thought you'd be more pleased.
No, I am pleased, really I am.
I've just got a lot on my mind.
Sorry.
I've also advertised
for a new footman.
He'll be second footman, won't he?
As to that, I will not pronounce
at this stage. Try to find a man
with something about him.
I want the house
to be properly represented.
Is that aimed at me?
If the cap fits, wear it.
You're very quiet.
You'll never guess what.
I've had a letter from Ethel.
She wants to meet me,
but she won't come here.
What for? And why not?
She'd be uncomfortable.
Why, particularly?
Never you mind.
I think I'll ask Mrs Crawley
if we can meet there.
Heaven knows what Ethel
wants of us this time.
Cora said you were looking for me.
I've stolen the nursery
as a sitting room.
This is the paper,
unless you hate it.
Oh.
Is that all?
Why? What did you think it was?
Cora said you'd been
to the doctor earlier.
I wondered why.
To find something for my hay fever.
What will we use for a day nursery
should the need arise?
I think we can worry about that
a little further down the line.
Oh, thank you, my dear,
that's very kind.
How much do I owe you? A guinea.
A guinea?
For a bottle of scent?
Did he have a mask and a gun?
How are you? All right, I suppose.
I worry about you.
That sort of thing is so horrid.
Being jilted at the alter?
Yes, it is horrid,
multiplied by about
ten thousand million. Well...
You must keep busy.
What with? There's nothing
to do at the house,
except when we entertain.
There must be something
you can put your mind to. Like what?
Gardening? No, you can't be
as desperate as that.
Then what? Edith, dear,
you're a woman with a brain
and reasonable ability.
Stop whining
and find something to do.
I'm going out, Anna.
I've told Mrs Patmore.
I think everything's
under control for tonight.
What's the matter? Nothing.
Except...
I haven't had a letter
from Mr Bates in weeks.
I worry... I worry
that he's being gallant
and trying to set me free,
that he wants me to make a new life
without him.
I doubt it very much.
Then why would he be silent
like this and stop me visiting?
Obviously, I don't know why,
but I do know there'd be
a good reason.
Do you really think so?
I'd swear to it.
They know you tricked them.
Who knows what?
Mr Durrant's a dealer
on the outside.
What's that to do with me?
He's working for your cellmate.
You punched Craig
so they set you up,
but you hid the stuff,
turned the tables on them.
Now they're angry.
And what can they do?
Tell you what they can start doing.
Durrant reported you
to the governor for violence.
You're officially
a dangerous prisoner.
The governor won't fall for that.
When's the last time your wife came?
How many letters
have you received lately?
Thank God. What a relief.
I thought she'd given up on me.
Don't thank God till you know
what else is in store.
Stop talking!
Go on, then.
Tea spoon, egg spoon, melon spoon,
grapefruit spoon, jam spoon,...
Shall I tell you?
All right.
The bouillon spoon.
I thought soup spoons were the
same as table spoons? So they are,
but not for bouillon, which is drunk
from a smaller dish.
Off you go now, I must get on.
You're taking a lot of trouble
with Alfred.
I feel quite jealous.
I don't know why. He asked for help.
You never did.
It's very hard to begin.
Well, find a way,
we all have lives to lead.
Could you write to the Bryants
to say I want them to have Charlie?
We've already been down this path
to no avail. I know.
and I know I said a mother's love was
worth more than they had to give,
but I said it for me, not for him.
My dear, you mustn't do anything
until you're absolutely sure.
Mrs Hughes said we all have lives
to lead, but that isn't true.
I've got no life.
I exist, but barely. We know
the route you've taken.
It's good of you to have me here.
I work with others like you
to rebuild their lives.
Can't we work together
to find a way for you to keep
your son? With his grandparents,
Charlie can build a life that
is whatever he wishes it to be.
You and I working together
could never offer him that.
You want me to write to them again.
But leave it vague.
Say Ethel would like them
to keep in contact with their son.
I won't change my mind.
Nevertheless, that's what I'll do
then they'll be no disappointment.
If you'll forgive me,
we've a big dinner tonight.
Good day, ma'am. Ethel.
Ethel has had a very hard time
of it since she left us.
She's had great difficulty
making ends meet.
We know how she solved that problem.
Give my regards to Mr Molesley.
Until we meet again, my dear.
I had a coat.
It's there.
You will help Miss Parks.
Please, Mrs Bird.
Some manners wouldn't go amiss.
I do not believe it's part of my
duties to wait on the likes of her.
I'm sorry, but that's what I feel.
I don't want to sound anti-Catholic.
Why not? I am.
Not in any real way, I'm sure.
I don't want thumb screws
or the rack
but there's something
of Johnny Foreigner about them.
I've no time to talk
but tell them I'm all right.
I'm out of the flat,
they haven't stopped me.
Who hasn't stopped you?
Sybil?
'Hello?'
What's wrong? I've just had the most
peculiar conversation with Sybil.
She kept on about being
out of the flat
and nobody had stopped her and...
Stopped her from doing what?
I don't know. She suddenly
put down the telephone.
Dinner is served, My Lady.
Do you find the War
has driven the people
back into the churches
or further away than ever?
Behold,
I stand at the door and knock.
Someone sounds very angry.
Or very wet. Or both.
Do you any have luggage, sir? I
barely have the clothes I stand in.
Where are they? They're in the...
Tom! What's happened? Where's Sybil?
I had to get away,
leave her to follow.
I made arrangements.
She'll be on her way now.
Why are you here?
Why must she follow you alone?
I can explain.
There's a dinner going on but I'll
tell them you're here. No, don't.
No-one must know. I'll tell you
it all when they're gone.
What's the matter?
Tom!
Get some dry clothes of Matthew's.
I'll come when the coast is clear.
Would you ask Mrs Hughes to sort
some food out for him? Yes, My Lady.
An idiotic man delivering a village
pamphlet. Can you imagine,
in this weather,
at this time of night?
It's Branson. He wouldn't come in.
Why not?
Is Sybil with him?
What's going on? She's not here
but apparently she's coming soon.
He'll explain
when our guest has gone.
Something to look forward to.
Other men have normal sons-in-law
who farm or preach or serve
their country.
No family is ever what it seems.
Do you think he's on the run
from the police? Don't be daft.
He hadn't the money for a taxi
from the station.
Maybe he fancied the walk.
Yes, he probably loves
a night walk in the pouring rain.
What room is he in?
I'll take that, thank you.
So there'll be no more gossip
on that subject tonight.
They turned everyone
out of the castle,
Lord and Lady Drungore,
their sons and servants,
and then they set fire to it.
What a tragedy. Well, yes and no.
That house was hideous,
but of course, that is no excuse.
No, it is not.
What was your involvement?
Who says I was involved? You know
a lot about it if you weren't.
Why are you running away?
And what's Sybil's part in this?
She's not involved. They think I was
part of it, one of the instigators.
The police are looking for you?
I couldn't go home.
If they took me,
I wouldn't get a fair hearing.
You gave them Sybil
while you saved yourself?
I don't think they'll hold her,
but if they do,
I'm ready to go back and face
the consequences. You'd better be.
You must see the Home Secretary.
And say what? The police say
he was there, he says he wasn't.
I didn't say I wasn't there.
Why were you?
For the fun of seeing
private property destroyed?
Those places are different for me.
I don't see charm
and gracious living.
I see something horrible.
It's a jungle castle,
I rather agree. Mama,
you are not helping.
But when I saw them
standing there with their children,
all of them in tears
watching their home burn,
I was sorry. I admit it.
I don't want their type to govern
Ireland, I want a free state,
but I was sorry.
Never mind that.
What's happened to Sybil?
We agreed that
I should leave at once
and that she'd close the flat
and follow.
I got the last boat so she won't
be here before tomorrow. Good God!
You abandon a pregnant woman
in a land that's not her own
while you run for it?! You have
to go to London, for Sybil's sake.
You have to see Mr Short. I don't
have to do anything! I... Go to bed!
I'll give you my answer
in the morning.
Of course, she married beneath her.
Says the Habsburg Archduke!
What if he has to go to prison?
What then?
That's enough of that, thank you,
Miss O'Brien.
Bedtime, I think.
I'm going up. Good night.
I'll try to keep them quiet,
but to be honest,
I knew it would happen.
I knew he'd bring shame
on this house.
It sounds as if he's on the run
from the police
and that Lady Sybil is languishing
in a dungeon in Dublin.
Let's wait and see
what the morning brings.
What in God's name is it?
An electric toaster. I've given it
to myself as a treat.
If it's any good, I'll suggest one
for the upstairs breakfasts.
Is it not enough that we're
sheltering a dangerous revolutionary?
Could you not have spared me that?
You've always had that.
Hello.
Can we help you?
I'm here to see Mr Carson.
Who's this?
Jimmy Kent, at your service.
I'm Mr Barrow, His Lordship's valet.
I'm hoping to be
His Lordship's footman,
which is why
I'm looking for Mr Carson.
What's the matter? Have you all been
turned into pillars of salt?
May I help? I've come
for the interview.
I see.
Well, if you'll wait there.
I want to make it clear that whatever
I do, it's for Sybil and not you.
I find your actions despicable,
whatever your beliefs.
You speak of Ireland suffering,
and I don't contradict you,
but Ireland cannot prosper
until this savagery is put away.
Yes, but you must keep Tom out
of prison. I'll go to London today.
I'll arrange an interview. I won't
come home till I've seen Short.
Thank you. I know it's right. For
him. And for Sybil and this family.
I suppose so. Let me know
if Sybil gets in touch.
She won't. She won't give them
anything to trace her by.
What a harsh world you live in.
We all live in a harsh world,
but at least I know I do.
I see you've been working for
the Dowager, Lady Anstruther.
Yes, but she's closed up the house
and gone to live in France.
She begged me to go with her
but I didn't fancy it.
I didn't think I'd like the food.
She begged you, did she?
You know what women can be like.
Not, I suspect, as well as you do.
Is it safe?
Right, Charlie,
let's put your hat on.
Make you look nice and smart.
Be a good boy for Mummy, yeah?
Yeah.
Come on.
Thank you for letting us come.
Why have we come? To hear more guff
about a mother's love? Mr Bryant,
that's not fair. Isn't it?
We know what you are now, Ethel.
We know how far you've fallen.
I didn't want Mrs Bryant to be in
the same room as you. He means...
How do you know? It's not hard
to find out about a woman like you.
I could give you a list
of your clients.
You've had me followed?
Didn't you think we'd keep
a check on our grandson?
We're not judging you.
I'm judging her.
I judge her and I find her wanting.
Ethel, we've decided
to offer you some money,
to make things easier
so you won't have to...
Unless you don't want to give it up.
Well, that's very generous,
isn't it, Ethel?
It throws a different light
on things.
Oh, there's Mrs Bird with the tea.
Would you like to help me, Ethel?
Look what I've got for you.
A teddy. That's right.
Should I not take it in, then?
I can do that.
I'm sure I don't need your help.
Thank you, Mrs Bird.
Ethel, you don't have to do this.
You have a choice. You mean I should
take money from that man?
It won't be much.
Enough to keep us from starving.
Even if Charlie doesn't go
to a famous school or university,
you'll be there to give him love.
Yeah. I suppose Mr Crawley went
to a famous school and university.
I see.
Thank you, Mrs Crawley.
When do you want it to happen?
Tomorrow night.
Want Mr Durrant? No.
Not him.
Tell Turner, he's straight.
Don't tell him till the afternoon.
Why are you doing this?
Why are you helping me?
I can't stand Craig.
You do that very neatly, my dear.
I was trained by Mrs Hughes.
She was a good worker,
even though things
haven't gone so well lately.
I hope that you can accept
our offer, Ethel,
and that we can be friends.
We both wish you well, don't we?
I don't wish you ill. I'll say that.
I can't accept your offer.
And we won't be friends.
What?
Not even for Charlie's sake?
I think you love my son, Mr Bryant.
I don't think
you're a nice or kind man,
but I believe you love my boy.
So you'll be pleased
by what I've come here to say.
Any news while I was out?
No. Perhaps the Home Secretary
won't see him.
Papa will pull some strings
until he does.
A-ha, you've started on the Augean
task. How are you getting on?
Not badly. I'm beginning
to get a sense of how it works.
It's probably best
you tackle it by yourself.
Ah, Carson. May we please have
some tea? Oh, of course, My Lady.
Anna said you're interviewing
footmen today. That is correct.
Have you chosen the lucky winner?
Not yet. There were two candidates
when it came down to it.
One was steady but not much else,
but the ladies downstairs
want the other one.
Why is that?
I don't know precisely, unless
it's because he's more handsome.
Of course it's because
he's more handsome.
Do pick him
and cheer us all up a bit.
Alfred's nice, but he looks like
a puppy rescued from a puddle.
This new one seems
very sure of himself.
You can manage that, can't you?
I suppose I could, sir.
It's settled, then. Tell the maids
they can buy their valentines.
So be it, My Lady.
But Alfred is very good, you know.
He's very willing,
even if he is Miss O'Brien's nephew.
Clearly, nothing worse
could be said of any man.
He'll want to say goodbye.
I give you my blessings for your
whole life long, my darling boy.
You won't remember that, or me,
but they'll stay
with you all the same.
Let's not make a meal of it.
Mummy...
I'll write to you.
I'll never see my son again.
Never is a long time, Ethel,
but you were right,
he does love Charlie,
and not just for his father's sake.
I must be going.
I'll say goodbye.
You've done
a hard thing today, Ethel,
the hardest thing of all.
You don't agree, do you?
I don't want to make you doubt
now that it's happened.
You've done the right thing
for the boy, Ethel,
whatever Mrs Crawley may say,
begging your pardon, ma'am.
Perhaps you're right. I am,
until we live in a very
different world from this one.
Well, then,
I should be away.
What chance is there
for a woman like her?
She's taken the road to ruin.
There's no way back.
Stand up! Against the wall,
the pair of you.
What you looking for?
Just keep quiet.
Mr Turner. Well, well.
A very mysterious package,
I don't think.
Craig,
what do you call this?
I don't know. I've done nothing.
You'd better come with us, Craig.
You'll be sorry.
Oh, thank God!
I'm so sorry.
It's all right.
They didn't try to stop me.
It doesn't mean
they won't come after us,
unless Papa can persuade them
otherwise.
How could you have left her
to fend for herself?
It wasn't like that. We thought this
might happen and decided what to do.
The question is what now? You must
not travel before the baby's born.
Tom wants it to be born in Dublin.
He won't hold you to that now.
Won't this be the first place
they look?
How could you be part of it?
The Drungores are like us.
She came out with me,
she was Laura Dunsaney then.
How could you dance round her burning
house? It's horrible. He didn't
and isn't dancing now.
Come in.
Telegram for you, My Lady.
Your father's coming home.
He's seen Mr Short.
What happened? He doesn't say,
only that neither of you
is to leave Downton.
You're back.
I am.
Anything happened here?
There's a new footman.
Came today. How was London?
Quite fun as a matter of fact.
Has the firebrand been saved?
That's not for me to say,
is it, Mr Molesley?
I'd better take these upstairs.
You got the job, then?
I'm on my way, Mr Barrow.
They say you were a footman once.
That's right. Can I come to you
if there's anything I need to know?
Certainly. Why not?
Never go back to Ireland?
Impossible. You'll be put in prison.
It's the best I could manage.
Surely they need proof to ban a man
from his own country.
They have more proof
than Tom will concede. Is that fair?
He's admitted to being there. He's
told you. But he didn't tell me
he attended meetings where attacks on
the Anglo-Irish were planned.
I was always against
any personal violence, I swear it.
So at least we can sleep
in our beds.
Maybe, but you weren't against
the destruction of property.
That was worse than I expected.
What was the deal you made
with the Home Secretary?
They don't want
to make a martyr of him.
With Sybil they think they could have
another Maud Gonne or Lady Gregory.
Lady Gregory. Countess Markievicz.
Why are the Irish rebels
so well born?
Whatever the reason, I don't want
Sybil to join their ranks.
Mercifully, nor do
the Irish authorities.
If Tom can stay away,
they'll leave him alone.
I can't be kept away from Ireland.
You'll be arrested the moment
you touch dry land.
Now, then, do what
Mr Carson tells you.
I know what I'm about.
Are you all right, Alfred? Yes.
Shouldn't I be carrying the pork
and you the veg? I'm first footman.
Never mind that, go.
Isn't Alfred first footman?
That's for Mr Carson to decide.
By heck, it's nice to think we're
running at full strength again.
Really? I'm running at full strength
with no-one to help.
All in good time, Daisy.
All in good time.
What do you mean
you wrote to a newspaper?
No lady writes to a newspaper.
What about Lady Sarah Wilson?
She's the daughter of a duke.
She's a Churchill.
The Churchills are different.
Have we no Churchill blood?
Granny's right.
Can somebody write that down?
It's good to have strong views
but notoriety is never helpful.
I've sent it now.
It won't be published.
Thank you for the vote
of confidence.
This is our new footman, Mama.
What do we call you? Jimmy.
James, Your Ladyship. This is James.
Welcome to Downton, James.
Thank you, My Lord.
Well done, Carson.
That must've cheered up the maids.
He looks like a footman
in a musical review. Poor Alfred.
We mustn't allow him to be
overshadowed. Quite right, My Lady.
Hard work and diligence weigh more
than beauty in the real world.
If only that were true.
I've never been James in my life.
I was Jimmy to Lady Anstruther.
I don't care if you were
Father Christmas.
You're James now and will stay James
while you're at Downton.
He thinks he's the big cheese,
make no mistake.
That's because he is.
He's nice, that new bloke, isn't he?
Why do you say that?
Oh, only an impression, that's all.
If you'll excuse me,
I'm going to bed.
Can you tell the others?
Tomorrow, we'll make some plans.
I don't know how.
You've lived out of Ireland before,
surely you can again.
Ireland's coming of age,
I need to be part of that,
but I know what you've done
for me, kept me free,
and I am grateful, truly.
Poor chap, I'm sure he is grateful.
No, he's not.
He says it to keep the peace
with Sybil.
But I only rescued him
for her sake so we're even.
Did you get a chance to look through
the books they brought in?
As a matter of fact, I did. Could
you make them out? I think so.
I was waiting for a good moment
to discuss them. Oh?
Yes. There were some aspects
of the way things have been done
I wasn't quite sure about.
You sound like Murray.
Do I? He's always going on about how
we should overhaul this or that.
Nothing's ever right for him.
Well, I hesitate to say it...
We should let them get in here.
We can talk about it another time.
These came for you, Bates.
When? When did they come?
They came when
you were out of favour.
Now you're in favour again.
Why? What have I done?
Just watch out for Mr Durrant.
You're not a favourite with him.
What...
Are you going to take that over me?
I was just making myself some toast.
You have to set the number
on the dial and I set it too high
but I've got the hang of it now.
Would you like a piece?
I thought Mr Branson might try
to burn the house down
but I didn't think you would.
No?
You should never take anything
for granted, Mr Carson.
No, no, no. Not now.
You never told me
you went to those meetings.
I never told you I didn't.
What else haven't you told me?
All I know is I can't stay here,
not for long.
You must, and so must I.
And you must let the baby
be born here.
You're very free with your musts.
I will not be free
with our child's chances.
We need peace and safety.
Downton can offer us both.
God in heaven! "Earl's daughter
speaks out for women's rights"!
What? "In a letter
to this newspaper today
Lady Edith Crawley,
daughter of the Earl of Grantham,
condemns the limitations
of the women's suffrage Bill
and denounces the Government's aims
to return women
to their pre-war existence."
You said they wouldn't print it.
That's most impressive.
Don't say you support her?
Of course I do, and so do you,
when you've had a chance to think
about it. So I should hope.
What do you think, Carson?
I'd rather not say.
Anna... Yes?
There's quite a packet of letters
arrived for you earlier.
Are they all from Mr Bates?
It looks like it.
Why so many at once?
I neither know nor care,
just as long as I've got them.
Thanks for sticking up for me
last night.
It won't make any difference.
No, but it's good
to know you're on my side.
I am on your side, Alfred.
In fact,
there's something
I've wanted to say.
You've got my attention. Well...
Here we are, Daisy. I'd like
to introduce Miss Ivy Stuart,
the new kitchen maid. And this is
Daisy, my assistant cook.
My, aren't you a sight
for sore eyes, Miss Stuart!
That's enough of that. Alfred's
a footman, so don't listen to him.
Shoo!
Tell me if you need any help.
Sorry, Daisy, what were you saying?
Nothing. Don't matter now.
I hope we're going to get on.
We don't have to get on,
we have to work together.
A situation has arisen
and I'm not quite sure
which way to turn.
Obviously, if you've turned to me.
Robert won't discuss the matter
and Mary is affronted
by the very mention of it,
but given that I've sunk my own
fortune alongside everyone else's
into... Into Downton.
..I feel a duty,
apart from anything else,
to do what I can.
About?
Downton is being mismanaged,
cousin Violet,
and something must be done.
The thing is how do I do it without
putting people's noses out of joint?
Oh, my dear. Oh, I doubt
there's a way to achieve that.
You must do what needs to be done,
of course, but...
I think I can safely say a great
many noses will be out of joint.
Edith has been invited
to write a newspaper column.
When will she get an offer
to appear on the London stage?
I thought you might work here
for a while. You thought?
I'm always a failure in this family.
She meant you to be hanged for her
suicide. It was her revenge.
What a revenge. Mrs Crawley's hired
a prostitute to manage her house?
I don't remember Ethel
as a great cook.
Please tell Mr Barrow him to keep
his distance. What are you implying?
Sync and corrected by
www.MY-SUBS.com